Frantz Felix

frantz.c.felix@gmail.com | (856) 383 9440 | Seattle, WA 98122

Portfolio: https://bit.ly/FrantzPortfolio GitHub: https://github.com/FrantzCFelix/ LinkedIn: https://linkedin.com/in/frantz-felix/

SUMMARY

Full-stack developer with a background in Computer Science, specializing in the MERN stack. Toastmaster with effective 'off-the-cuff' communication skills. Recognized among peers as a creative problem solver, knowledgeable programmer, and a team player. Strong interest in full-stack development; building intuitive, user-friendly applications.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

JavaScript (ES6) | React | jQuery | CSS | HTML | Bootstrap | Express | MySQL | MongoDB | Sequelize | Git | Heroku | Socket.io | PWAs | Google Map APIs | InVision Studio (comparable to Figma)

EDUCATION

Full Stack Web Development Certificate | University of Washington | 11/2019 - 5/2020

- Achieved a thorough understanding of web development and became a proficient MERN Stack Developer.
- Worked with other aspiring developers in a collaborative environment to strengthen soft skills and complete projects that challenged my skill set.
- Full list of technologies and algorithms covered http://bit.ly/UWBC-FullStack

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science | Rutgers University | 2017

3.23 GPA | Minor in Animation | Dean's List Honoree Spring 2016

EXPERIENCE

Teaching Assistant | **University of Washington Coding Bootcamp** | 09/2020 - Present *Trilogy Education Services - New York, NY - (Remote Seattle, WA)*

- Mentor and engage students in the classroom by working together with other instructors.
- Guide students to overcome technical hurdles in both their group projects and individual study.

Front End Developer | Online Studio™ Platform | 01/2019 to 07/2019 CodeStream Studios LLC - Dallas, TX – (Remote, Seattle, WA)

- Developed front end application components using Vue.JS framework, enhancing UI functionality.
- Implemented unit testing to existing code base and added new routines using Jest, improving code reliability.

PROJECTS

Book-It-Yourself | Frontend/Backend | https://github.com/agtravis/book-it-yourself | https://bit.ly/book-it-youself | Social media site that connects smaller artists, bands, etc., with each other and promoters.

- Organized team work schedule and milestones using a Kanban board, enabling on-time project completion.
- Created the map that shows posting locations using several key Google Map APIs:
 - W3's Geolocation API to find where the user is, Google Places API for validation, and the Map JS API for the map markers (made as a React component).
- Implemented bi-directional communication between users using Socket.io and React.

RinqyDink Arcade | Frontend/Backend | https://github.com/FrantzCFelix/RINQYDINK | https://github.com/FrantzCFelix/RINQYDINK | https://bit.ly/RinqyDinkArcade | <a href="https://bit.ly

- Designed a platformer multiplayer game using JavaScript, Socket.io, and the Phaser 3 game engine.
- Built a chat room between all logged in users using Socket.io.
- Deployed application to Heroku cloud.
- Implemented a linter and used Travis CI to ensure code was uniform to reduce merge conflicts.

Eventifiy-Your-Map | Frontend | http://github.com/FrantzCFelix/Eventify-your-map | http://bit.ly/Eventify-your-map | Locate events in your city with an interactive map.

- Returned data from Ticketmaster API based on user selected criteria, using JavaScript.
- Visualized event locations on google maps using data from event query.